<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>violent on Vincent&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/violent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in violent on Vincent&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/violent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Violent Video Games: A Simple Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/04/01/violent-video-games-a-simple-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/01/violent-video-games-a-simple-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Note: All source code can be found on this Github repo.
Introduction In the last post, I explored the existing literature on violent video games and violent crime. If you recall, the studies I shared found that an increase in violent video game sales was associated with a decrease in violent crime.
To see whether these counterintuitive results held up, I ran a quick and dirty linear regression with violent video game sales as the predictor variable and the violent crime rate in the US as the outcome variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violent Video Games: A (Biased) Look at the Research</title>
      <link>/2020/03/30/violent-video-games-literature-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/30/violent-video-games-literature-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I was 11 years old, I begged my dad to buy me Fallout 3. Now, Fallout 3 is a highly immersive video game with a complex storyline that grapples with difficult moral questions. It also happens to be a game where you can shoot people and watch their heads explode. My dad, knowing this, prudently declined to purchase the game for his 11 year old. So instead I went over to my friend’s house to play Call of Duty, a game where you can shoot people and watch their heads explode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>